<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Other work on Christopher Prosser</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4321/other/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Other work on Christopher Prosser</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4321/other/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ITV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/itv/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/itv/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2015 I have worked as a data analyst (what people in the media call a ‘&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Psephology&#34;&gt;psephologist&lt;/a&gt;’) for the ITV News overnight election results programme.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since the 2016 EU referendum I have run ITV&amp;rsquo;s result projection model, which tries to work out what the final outcome is going to be before all the results have come in. This happened slightly by accident. One of the challenges of covering the 2016 referendum was that, unlike a general election, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t compare the results to what had happened a few years previously. To help ITV&amp;rsquo;s on screen experts Professors Jane Green and Colin Rallings make sense of the results as they came in, I estimated a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britishpollingcouncil.org/briefing-spotlight-on-mrp/&#34;&gt;MRP forecast&lt;/a&gt; of the referendum outcome. Jane and Colin could then compare the results to my forecast and say whether the results were looking good for Leave or Remain. As the results came in, I could also adjust the model and estimate the probability of Leave or Remain winning the referendum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/media/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/media/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As well as my work with &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/other/itv/&#34;&gt;ITV&lt;/a&gt;, I give regular interviews to the national and international media, generally talking about something to do with British elections or polling. I&amp;rsquo;ve appeared on flagship programmes such as &lt;em&gt;Newsnight&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Today&lt;/em&gt;, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been interviewed by most of the major British newspapers, including the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Times&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Telegraph&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Economist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;cp_newsnight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;newsnight&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I particularly enjoy doing podcasts, because they give me the opportunity to talk about things in more depth, and I&amp;rsquo;ve appeared on podcasts such as Sky News&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;All Out Politics&lt;/em&gt;, the &lt;em&gt;Guardian Politics Weekly&lt;/em&gt;, and the Times&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Red Box Politics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>McDougall Trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/mcdougall/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/mcdougall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2025 I became one of the trustees of the McDougall Trust, a small charity which exists to advance knowledge and understanding of electoral democracy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The trust:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Owns the academic journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/journals/rrep20/about-this-journal&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Representation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Funds the annual McDougall Fund Prize awarded by the Political Studies Association for a PhD thesis about elections, electoral systems and representation.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Held a substantial archive of material relating to elections and electoral reform, including the earliest records of the Proportional Representation Society and the Electoral Reform Society. Most of the material was recently transferred to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://warwick.ac.uk/services/library/mrc/news/?newsItem=8a1785d78ce92907018d3b388e9962de&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Modern Records Centre&lt;/a&gt; at the University of Warwick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Encourages, supports, and provides research about electoral democracy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can read more about us on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcdougall.org.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;McDougall Trust website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peer review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like many academics, I spend some of my time reviewing submissions for academic journals, publishers, and funding bodies. I also like measuring things and keeping track of them, even if there&amp;rsquo;s no point in doing so.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; I think it can be useful to share this sort of information &amp;ndash; no one really knows how much reviewing other people do, which makes it hard to know if you are doing a lot or a little of something. I have no idea if I do more or less reviewing than most people in my field &amp;ndash; I know some who do more, but other who do less. In any case, here is a brief record of the reviews I have done during my career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Electoral Studies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/electstudies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/electstudies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2023 I joined the editorial board of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/journal/electoral-studies&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Electoral Studies&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Mostly that means I &#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:4321/other/review/&#34;&gt;review&lt;/a&gt; lots of papers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;From 2013-15 I also worked as a editorial assistant for &lt;em&gt;Electoral Studies&lt;/em&gt;, working under Geoff Evans. If you submitted a paper during that period you&amp;rsquo;re welcome for the speedy processing of your paper/sorry it took so long to proceess your paper (delete as appropriate).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>World Squash Federation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/wsf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/wsf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In 2018-19 I was part of the World Squash Federation&amp;rsquo;s (WSF) Voting Structure and Representation Review Group, which was tasked with examinnig the voting system the WSF uses to make decisions at the general meetings.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Voting rules in international sporting bodies such as the WSF raise interesting questions about equality and representation &amp;ndash; different countries have wildly varying levels of participation in squash, and there are large differences in the resources that national squash federations can wield. Should each country have equal voting rights, or should places with more squash players have more say in what the WSF does? If you give some countries more votes than others, how many more do they get, and what measure do you use decide how many votes each country gets?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Committee on Standards in Public Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:4321/other/cspl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:4321/other/cspl/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of my graduate studies I did some work for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gov.uk/government/organisations/the-committee-on-standards-in-public-life/about&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Committee on Standards in Public Life&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  (CSPL), the public body set up to advise the Prime Minister about of the ethical standards across public life, helping them analyze two surveys.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first survey looked at public awareness of police accountability (elected Police and Crime Commissioners &amp;ndash; PCCs &amp;ndash; had been introduced a few years earlier). The short version is that while the majority of people survyed trusted the police and had heard of PCCs, they knew very little about how PCCs worked and what they did, and were not particularly interested in policing matters. You can read the report I wrote  &lt;a href=&#34;https://assets.publishing.service.gov.uk/government/uploads/system/uploads/attachment_data/file/439221/Public_Awareness_of_Police_Accountability_report_final_draft.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
